|3rdparty|External applications
|accessdenied|Access denied
|actions|Actions
|adaptcase?Enable/ disable standardization of titles and artists, e.g. changing "The Beatles" to "Beatles, The"
|adaptcase|Standardize titles
|addcontentdir|Add new content directory
|addlevel|Add level
|addnode|Add node
|add|Add
|adobepath?Full path to the Adobe Photoshop Album catalog file (.psa).
|adobepath|Adobe Photoshop Album
|advanceddefault|Advanced default navigation
|advancedsetup|Advanced Setup
|album|Album
|allname?Title of the - ALL - entry in the nodes of the navigation tree.
|allname|- ALL -
|allowedmaxmem|Maximum memory available for the server
|allpictures?Name for 'All Photos' folder (server default used if left empty).
|allpictures|All Photos
|allstations|All Stations
|alltracks?Name for 'All Tracks' folder (server default used if left empty). 
|alltracks|All Tracks
|allvideos?Name for 'All Videos' folder [server default used if left empty]. 
|allvideos|All Videos
|artistindex|Artist Index
|artists|Artists
|artist|Artist
|basicsetup|Basic Setup
|browse|Browse
|builddate|Server built date
|cachedir?The server caches transcoded songs and scaled photos to enable faster access to frequently used items. The directory where these items are stored can be set by means of this option.
|cachedir|Cache directory
|cachemaxsize?This is the maximum size of the cache in KB. If there is more space needed the oldest not used file from the cache is deleted first. If an empty string is specified, the cache size is not limited.
|cachemaxsize|Maximum cache size
|cancel|Cancel
|cdkey?Please enter a registration key to activate the server. If the server software was bundled with your media receiver, the registration key is provided by the manufacturer. Please check CD and documentation. In all other cases a key has to be obtained from the <a href="http://www.twonkyvision.com/Online-Shop/" target="_blank">TwonkyVision Online Shop</a>.
|cdkey|Registration key
|clearlog|Clear logs
|client/security|Clients/Security
|clientautoenable|Enable sharing for new media receivers automatically
|clients|Media Receivers
|compilationsdir?Comma separated list of directories (or substrings) which shall be handled as music compilations
|compilationsdir|Compilation directories
|composers|Composers
|composer|Composer
|configlocation|Configuration file at
|configrightclick|Open configuration page
|containers|Containers
|contentdir?Directories where the server shall scan for content. Each directory can be limited to a certain content type. The default setting will scan for all content types. Sharing can be temporarily disabled  by unchecking the directory.
|contentdir|Content Locations
|content|Content
|custom|Custom
|date|Date
|days|days
|day|Day
|dbdir?Directory where the TwonkyMedia database and cache shall be stored
|dbdir|MediaServer database directory
|dbupdate|Last database change
|debugging|Debugging
|delete|Delete
|description|Description
|enableweb?The access to the server configuration through the web can be limited by means of this option to the local browser. Please note that for NAS you need public access!
|enableweb|Web access
|expired?Your trial version has expired.
|faq|FAQ
|files|Files
|firstSteps|First Steps
|folderprefix?Folder prefix string to be prefixed to all folder names in folder navigation to help you differentiate folders from content items at the media receiver.
|folderprefix|Folder prefix string
|folder|Folder
|followlinks?With this option you can allow the file scanner to follow symbolic links (UNIX/Linux only).
|followlinks|Follow links
|forum|Forum
|friendlyname?Name of the media server as displayed by media receivers. By means of the macro %HOSTNAME% you can add the actual host name, e.g. TwonkyMedia [%HOSTNAME%].
|friendlyname|Server name
|genreindex|Genre Index
|genres|Genres
|genre|Genre
|getlog|View log file
|hours|hours 
|httpport?Set to port number of http server, set to 0 for dynamical port allocation (default port is 9000).
|httpport|HTTP server port
|internetradio|Internet Radio
|invalidkey?Invalid key
|ipodlike|iPod-like
|items|Items
|ituneslib?Full path to the iTunes library file.
|ituneslib|iTunes library file
|keyinuse?This key is already in use by another instance of the server.
|keymismatch?This key is not valid  for this version of the server.
|keyword|Keyword
|language?Language in which configuration pages and the navigation tree on the media receiver will be presented.
|language|Language
|licensedays|Days left
|licenseinfo|License information
|license|License
|localweb|Local access to web configuration pages
|loglevel?Specify the kind of information to log for debugging purposes. If you click the button "view log file", the content of the current log file will be presented in a separate browser window.
|loglevel|Log level
|maxmemexceeded|The maximum available memory is exceeded. Not all content can be served!
|mediabrowser|Media Browser
|memoryusage|Memory Usage
|memoryusedfor|Memory used for
|memory|Memory
|miscellaneous|Miscellaneous
|month|Month
|musicclient|Music-only receiver
|musicnode10|Music node 10 
|musicnode1|Music node 1 
|musicnode2|Music node 2 
|musicnode3|Music node 3 
|musicnode4|Music node 4 
|musicnode5|Music node 5 
|musicnode6|Music node 6
|musicnode7|Music node 7
|musicnode8|Music node 8
|musicnode9|Music node 9
|musicnode?An individual music navigation tree with up to 10 nodes may be specified by this option. For each node the name to be presented in the navigation tree and the node type have to be specified. In addition an alpha sub-grouping may be introduced by specifying the number of characters per group.
|musicnode|Music node
|musictracks|Music tracks
|musictree|Music tree
|name|Name
|naming|Naming
|navigation|Navigation Tree
|netgearrtp?Enable Netgear RTP to the more stable RTP streaming for Netgear MP101 receivers. This option is only available on Linux/UNIX.
|netgearrtp|Netgear RTP
|networkinterfaces|Network Interfaces
|network|Network
|nicrestart?Enable/ disable dynamic restart of the server on any NIC change. Note that server restart will result in stream interruption!
|nicrestart|Restart on NIC changes
|norescale?With this option photo rescaling can be suppressed. This option is mainly needed for NAS devices with low CPU and memory.
|norescale|Disable photo rescaling
|nosearch?With this option server-side search support can be suppressed. If search is enabled ROKU receivers will provide their own navigation structure and ignore the one provided by the server.
|nosearch|Disable search for ROKU receivers
|no|no
|performance|Performance
|picturenode1|Photo node 1
|picturenode2|Photo node 2
|picturenode3|Photo node 3
|picturenode4|Photo node 4
|picturenode5|Photo node 5
|picturenode?An individual photo navigation tree with up to 5 nodes may be specified by this option. For each node the name to be presented in the navigation tree and the node type have to be specified. 
|picturenode|Photo node
|pictures|Photos
|picturetree|Photo tree
|playlistlastplayed?Name of the auto generated playlist 'last played', leave empty if this playlist should not be added to the navigation tree.
|playlistlastplayed|Last played
|playlistmostplayed?Name of the auto-generated playlist 'most played', leave empty if this playlist should not be added to the navigation tree.
|playlistmostplayed|Most played
|playlistnumentries?Maximum number of entries for auto generated playlists, 0 to disable auto generated playlists.
|playlistnumentries|Number of entries for auto generated playlists
|playlists?Name of the playlists node in the navigation tree, leave empty if this node shall not be included in the navigation tree.
|playlists|Playlists
|publicweb|Public access to web configuration pages
|quickstartup|First steps
|quit|Quit
|radiochannels|Radio Channels
|radiogenre?Shoutcast radio genres which shall be added to the station list. 
|radiogenre|Shoutcast genre filter
|radiorecorddir?Set this option to the directory where recorded mp3 files are to be stored
|radiorecorddir|Path to the recording directory
|radiorecordstationfile?Specify a .m3u playlist which includes the station names to be recorded
|radiorecordstationfile|Radio record stations file (.m3u)
|radioreread?Rescan time for Shoutcast radio stations in minutes, defaults to 60
|radioreread|Shoutcast reread time
|radiostations|Radio stations
|radio|Internet Radio
|randomizeplaylists?If this option is enabled the server will randomize .m3u files on startup. This option should only be used if media receivers do not directly support shuffle mode.
|randomizeplaylists|Randomize playlists
|rating|Personal rating
|rebuiltalert|Database is rebuilt from scratch. Depending on the amount of content, this might take a while.
|rebuiltdb|Rebuild database
|recordchannels|Record Channels
|references|References
|registeredaccount?The Server is registered.
|registeredfor?Registered for
|rescanalert|Rescan of content directories in progress.
|rescandirs|Rescan content directories
|rescanrightclick|Rescan content directories
|resetalert|All configuration options are now reset to default including language and navigation tree!
|resetdefaults|Reset to defaults
|resolution|Resolution
|restartalert|The server is restarting. This might take a few seconds.
|restartpending|Server restart pending
|restartrequired|Please note that some of the applied changes will only become effective after a server restarts!
|restartserver|Restart server
|rootmusic?Name for Music root folder, leave empty to suppress this folder.
|rootmusic|Music
|rootpicture?Name for Photos root folder, leave empty to suppress this folder.
|rootpicture|Photos
|rootvideo?Name for Video root folder, leave empty to suppress this folder.
|rootvideo|Videos
|rtpport?Set to port number of RTP server, set to 0 for dynamical port allocation (for Netgear MP101 only)
|rtpport|RTP server port
|savechanges|Save Changes
|scaninfo|Scan info
|scantime?This option specifies the rescan behavior of the server. If set to 0, automatic rescans are disabled. A positive value specifies the period between rescans of content directories in minutes. -1 enables the server to watch content directories automatically for new content without the need for rescans. 
|scantime|Rescan in minutes
|select|Select
|servedcontentitems|Served content items
|serverinfo|Server
|serverkind|Server type
|serverplatform|Server platform
|settings|Settings
|sharing|Sharing
|shopLink?Please obtain a license from the TwonkyVision Online Shop at www.twonkyvision.com/shop
|shop|Online Shop
|shoutcast?Name for Shoutcast Radio node, if left empty the server's default name will be used.
|shoutcast|Shoutcast node
|simpledefault|Simple default navigation
|songs|Songs
|station|Station
|status|Server status
|stopserver|Terminate server
|streambuffer?Buffer size in bytes which is used for streaming. Change this only if you experience video streaming problems. Value should be between 16000 and 128000.
|streambuffer|Streaming Buffer Size
|support|Support
|tagspicture?Name for 'Tags' folder e.g. from import of Adobe Photoshop Album Tags
|tagspicture|- Tags -
|terminaterightclick|Terminate Server
|title|Title
|totalmemoryused|Total memory used
|treetype?There is the choice of selecting different pre-configured navigation trees or defining a customized tree structure. For small content libraries the simple navigation tree is sufficient. For large content libraries the advanced navigation tree provides a better structured tree which allows faster access to individual items. A customized navigation tree can be defined through the advanced setup. 
|treetype|Navigation Tree Setup
|trialexpired|Trial expired, please visit http://www.twonkyvision.com 
|trialinfo?Trial period
|troubleshooting|Maintenance
|type|Type
|uptime|Server uptime
|usedmem|Used memory
|userkey|Generated license key
|username|User name
|userpwd|Password
|videonode1|Video node 1
|videonode2|Video node 2
|videonode3|Video node 3
|videonode4|Video node 4
|videonode5|Video node 5
|videonode?An individual video navigation tree with up to 5 nodes may be specified by means of this option. For each node the name to be presented in the navigation tree as well as the node type have to be specified. 
|videonode|Video node
|videos|Videos
|videotree|Video tree
|webaccess?Set a user name and a password to restrict access to these configuration pages. Leave both entries empty for unrestricted access.
|webconfigtitle|Configuration
|wrongversion?You cannot register TwonkyMedia with a TwonkyMusic license. Please acquire a TwonkyMedia license or download TwonkyMusic.
|year|Year
|yes|yes
|stopsharing|Stop Sharing
|startsharing|Start Sharing
|enabled|enabled
|remoteaccess|Remote access
|upload|Upload
|upnptimeout|Disable UPnP Timeout Messages
|upnptimeout?If the server disappears after exactly 30 minutes from your device, disable the UPnP timeout messages.
|httpremoteport|HTTP remote port
|httpremoteport?HTTP Server port for remote access. The server will apply the Username/Password settings to ALL incoming requests on this port. This port needs to be forwarded at your gateway.
|dyndns|Dynamic DNS 
|dyndns?This string is prefixed to all URLs the server presents on web pages for remote access. Give the whole prefix including the port here, e.g. "http://myhome.dyndns.org:9100"
|uploadenabled|enable upload
|uploadenabled?With upload you will be able to upload media via the media browser pages or with some mobile phones.
|uploadmusicdir|Upload Music Dir
|uploadmusicdir?Directory where uploaded music is placed. This directory should be under or part of a shared directory.
|uploadpicturedir|Upload Photo Dir
|uploadpicturedir?Directory where uploaded photos are placed. This directory should be under or part of a shared directory.
|uploadvideodir|Upload Video Dir
|uploadvideodir?Directory where uploaded videos are placed. This directory should be under or part of a shared directory.
|ignoredir?Comma separated list of directories which shall be ignored during content scans (substring match). If this setting is changed a 'rebuild database' is required!
|ignoredir|Ignore directories
|naming?Note: Changes on the naming will only have an effect if the navigation tree is set to 'custom'.
|vTunerweberror?vTuner Radio Stations are not accessible via the web browser
|dirmusic|Music
|dirpicture|Photos
|dirvideo|Videos
|save|Save
|createlog|Create log file
|rebuilddb?Rebuild the server database. Depending on the amount of content, this might take a while.
|resetdefaults?Sets all media server settings to default.
|resetdone?Settings have been reset.
|loglevelwhs?Click "Create log file" to log information for debugging purposes. Then click the button "view log file" to present the content of the log file in a separate browser window.
|sharingfolders|Media Sharing Folders
|sharedcontent|Shared Content
|remove|Remove
|edit|Edit
|foldertoggle|Double click a shared folder to toggle between enabled (green light) and disabled (red light).
|navigationtree|Navigation tree
|addfolder|Add a shared folder
|contenttype|Content type
|music|Music
|all|All
|selectfolder|Select a folder
|ok|OK
|contenttype?Choose the types of media that you would like to share from the selected folder.
|contenttypeedit?Choose the types of media that you would like to share.
|selectfolder?Browse the list of shared folders and select a folder or sub-folder to share.
|clienttoggle|Double click a media receiver to toggle between enabled (green light) and disabled (red light).
|sharingclients|Automatic sharing
|text|Description
|editclient|Edit media receiver
|newclient?Automatic media receiver detection does not always work. Receivers that are not identified can be adapted manually.
|editclient?Automatic media receiver detection does not always work. In this case the server simply assigns 'Generic DLNA client' and no client adaptation will take place. Media receivers that are not identified correctly can however be adapted manually by means of the list box above.
|client|Media Receiver
|newclient|New media receiver
|databasemanagement|Database management
|serverdefaults|Media server defaults
|logging|Logging
|resetclients|Reset list
|editfolder|Shared folder
|selectedfolder|Selected folder
|clienterror|Please select a receiver.
|foldererror|Please select a folder.
|stoplog|Stop logging
|enabledclients|Enabled Media Receivers
|clientnameerror|Please select a media receiver.
|serversettings|Media server settings
|serverdisabled|Server is currently disabled.
|legalserver|Wrong server version!
|uploaderror|Please select a folder.
|uploaddir|Upload folders
|uploaddir?Please set for each media type the folder into which you like to upload your media.
|radio?Enable/disable Shoutcast internet radio.
|uploadeditdir?Please choose the folder into which you like to upload your media.
|clientdetection?Lists of media receivers that have contacted the server. For each media receiver, the access to the server can be restricted. Automatic receiver detection does not always work. In this case the server simply assigns "Generic DLNA client" and no client adaptation will take place. Media receivers that are not identified correctly can however be adapted manually by means of the drop down menu above. To delete an entry, please set it to -/-. 
|ip|IP address of the server
|ip?This option should only be used, if DHCP is NOT in use! If an IP address is specified the server will not automatically bind to all network interfaces, but just to the specified ones. Please note, if this address is invalid the server will not start anymore!
|clientiperror|Please enter a valid IP address (i.e. 192.168.1.52).
|iptext|IP Address
|mactext|MAC Address
|clientmacerror|Please enter a valid MAC address (i.e. 00:18:C9:02:03:F1).
|allcontent|All content 
|musiconly|Music-only
|picturesonly|Pictures-only
|videoonly|Video-only
